# Muhammad A Khalid

Milpitas, CA, 95035 | (669) 350-5928 | akhalid.code@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/abdullahkhalid | github.com/akhalid88 | muhammadakhalid.com

# Summary

Full-Stack Web Developer proficient in JavaScript, React and creative problem-solving. Detailoriented and well-versed working in solo and collaborative environments. 8 years of prior IT experience gives me a unique perspective of understanding how to serve the customer as a developer.

#### **Skills**

Languages: Javascript, ES6, HTML5, CSS

Databases: MySQL, Sequelize, MongoDB, Mongoose

Tools: React, Node, Express, jQuery, Material-UI, Bootstrap, Bulma, RESTful APIs, MVC, Data

Structures, Algorithms, Big-O/Efficiency, Web APIs, Git/GitHub, Heroku, Auth0, Netlify

#### **Education**

**Certificate, Full Stack Web Development** 

**UC Berkeley Extension Bootcamp** 

Dec 2020 - Mar 2021

Berkeley, CA

Bachelor of Science, Game and Simulation Programming

DeVry University

Jun 2009 – Jun 2013 Fremont, CA

# **Projects**

Media Plug | http://bit.ly/media-plug-github | http://bit.ly/media-plug-project

- Personal digital bookshelf and community. Search and save books and add challenges
- Primary focus on backend API, Auth0, React routing, Controller of MVC framework
- Secondary focus on Material-UI integration, database models
- Built with React, MySQL, Express, Node, Auth0, Material-UI

#### **Work Experience**

### **Full Stack Web Development Tutor**

**Trilogy Education Services** 

Jun 2021 - Current

Remote

- Guide and assist students with homework assignments and programming concepts
- Grade student assignments providing relevant and detailed feedback

#### **Principal IT Infrastructure Specialist**

**Symantec Corporation** 

Jan 2018 - May 2020

Mountain View, CA

- Spearhead research and integration of new software for device performance monitoring that is utilized company-wide
- Primary resource for managing and maintaining enterprise backup solution
- Benchmarked and test potential new devices for fleet deployment
- Mac application packaging and deployment for employee use
- Develop reporting for application performance and uptime
- Performs preventative maintenance on a regular basis to minimize user downtime

### **Senior IT Support Specialist**

Aug 2016 - Dec 2017

Mountain View, CA

Symantec Corporation

- On-call and on-site support for Executive staff and floor
- Developed and maintained documentation for Executive runbook
- Collaborated with various teams to drive incident resolution

#### **Messaging VIP Support**

Symantec Corporation (Contract via ProUnlimited)

• Administered technical support for email migration

Jun 2016 – Aug 2016 Mountain View, CA • Developed cohesive IT resources to assist staff in day-to-day tasks

# IT Operations Supervisor/Senior Engineer

Oct 2012 - Apr 2016

Santa Clara, CA

- Sereniti IT Services
- On-call and on-site tech support for 15 clients based in and around the Bay Area
- Configured multiple servers and networks to support various needs of the clients
- Onboarded new clients by performing technology assessments and consultations

## Certifications

JAMF 200 Dec 2019
ITIL 2011 Foundation Oct 2018
Code42 Server Administrator Sep 2018